Historical Audiovisual Collection, 1912-2012 (bulk 1945-1996 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Historical Audiovisual Collection
1912-2012
1945-1996
AC047
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections. Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Princeton University Archives. 65 Olden Street Princeton, New Jersey 08540 USA
Over 2,300 items
Princeton University. Library. University Archives
This collection contains more than 2,300 items, including film, videotapes, compact discs, audio cassette tapes, reel-to-reel tape, and record albums and covers a broad range of topics including classical music, alumni reunions, lectures, and interviews.
The collection is the result of many contributions from individuals and departments within the University.
This collection has been divided into 7 broad series: Academics, Alumni, Campus Life, Events, Music, Public Talks, and Unidentified/Unknown Content. Subseries include Athletics (mostly football), Social Life, War/Military, Judicial Hearings, Theater, and Conferences/Meetings.
Some notable items are an audio recording of Jimmy Stewart singing in a Triangle Club production Spanish Blades, "Year of the Tiger" 1965 basketball highlights, PBS's MacNeil-Lehrer New Hour feature on the Hubble Telescope and Dr. Lyman Spitzer, "Looking Back: A Reflection of Black Alumni at Princeton" on the 150th Anniversary of the University, and Toni Morrison speaking about Paradise and appearing on various television and news shows. Other items of potential interest are the Celebrating Jewish-American Writer series, James Baker III '52, Secretary of State, at Princeton in various news clips, and the Class of 1945's World War II Oral History Project. There are also several dedication ceremonies of campus buildings.
The oldest item is a silent film from 1912 of John Grier Hibben's inauguration as president of Princeton University. The bulk of the items were produced from 1945 to 1996. Items from the 1920s through 1930s are generally alumni reunions, alumni trips, the Triangle Club Jazz Band, and football, through these topics can be found throughout the collection. Additional items from the 1940s include the Nassoons, the Ivy Quartet, the Princeton University Band and Princeton University Orchestra, the Class of 1945 Oral History project, and the Princeton Preceptorial of the Air. During the 1950s, the collection becomes more varied, adding the Princeton 54 through 56 series produced by NBC, the Tigertones, and Chapel Choir, the Glee Club, field trips with Professor Glenn Jepson (Department of Geology), and material featuring Adlai Stevenson, Herbert Hoover, and Dwight D. Eisenhower. Audiovisual material from the 1960s includes the Chamber Chorus, Gauss Seminars, a 1960 Princeton newsreel, Governor Rockefeller, Bill Bradley, and the Woodrow Wilson School dedication.
Items from the 1970s reflect the turbulent era with the 1970 Princeton strike, and Anti-ROTC demonstration, and a contemporary music concert. The Gauss Seminars continue during the decade. Other items are faculty meetings, public lectures, the Special Committee on Sponsored Research, a Judicial Committee hearing, and the Symphonic Band. There are many taped series in the 1980s, including such diverse topics as: Dennis Sullivan interviews with Princeton University Alumni, "The Photograph and the American Indian," molecular biology, Near Eastern studies, a US-Japanese trade conference, a Medicare conference, a Raphael symposium, Latin American studies, a global logistic symposium, the Woodrow Wilson School's Leadership in the Modern Presidency and Women Executives in State Government series, and regional and conservation symposium. Items from the 1990s include Martin Luther King Day celebrations, Toni Morrison, Nobel laureate in literature, "Defining Moments: Princeton at 250, Andrew Wiles, a student interview of members of Two Dickinson Road Vegetarian co-op, Princeton 250th anniversary Charter Weekend concert ("A Tribute to the Performing Arts"), and Princeton Conference of Higher Education.
Materials are described in chronological order within their series, with undated materials at the end of each series.
Materials that do not pertain to student academic performance or discipline, trustee issues, or faculty personnel matters are open. Restrictions are noted at the item-level description.
Mudd library does not have the facilities to view or listen to this material, and obsolete formats will need to be converted to a current format at the patron's expense before a reproduction can be made. Patrons should allow approximately four to six weeks for reproductions, especially if outdated formats are involved.
Searchable database located at: Princeton University Historical Audiovisual Collection
The collection is the result of many contributions from individuals and departments within the University. Many items are from the University Chapel and Communications Department. Several of the items have accession numbers with donor information.
Audiovisual materials on nitrate film were digitized and the film was decaccessioned and destroyed.
Princeton University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Princeton University -- Basketball.; Princeton University -- Bands.; Princeton University -- Choral organizations.; Princeton University -- Congresses.; Princeton University -- Football -- 20th century.; Princeton University -- History.; Princeton University -- Orchestras.; Princeton University -- Songs and music.; Princeton University -- Sports.; Princeton University -- Students -- Social conditions -- 20th century.; Princeton University. Triangle Club.; Debates and Debating -- New Jersey -- Princeton -- 20th century.; Audiovisual materials.; Compact discs.; Documentaries.; Lectures.; Newsreels.; Magnetic tapes.; Silent films.; Videotapes.; Videocassettes.; Born digital.; Princeton University
- Series 1: Academics, 1927-1999; 121 items
  The Academic series contains audiovisual materials pertaining to class lectures, presentations, and field studies. The Lectures and Interviews series contain public addresses, lectures, and debates.
  Series is described in chronological order, with undated materials at the end of each series.
  - Films of Field Trips -- Canada 1927 Niagara to Toronto, 637; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
    16 mm.
  - America Goes Back to School, 1938; 668; 3 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 61)
    President Dodds, Chapel Choir and Student Interviews. Created by WOR Recording. 33 1/3 rpm album.
  - Excavation, G.L. Jepsen, 1948; 1961; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Miscellaneous, G.L. Jepsen, 1949; 1960; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Horner site, G.L. Jepsen, 1950; AR.1997.006; 493; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Films of Field Trips, 1950; 642; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Traveling to mountains?, G.L. Jepsen, circa 1950; 1953; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Conference, G.L. Jepsen, 1951; AR.1997.006; 494; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Films of Field Trips -- Rattlesnake, SVP Field Conf, Fall Foliage, 1951; 643; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 182)
  - Birds-Quebec, G.L. Jepsen, 1953; AR.1997.006; 480; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Spanish, 1957; 41; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 129)
    Created by Princeton University. 16 mm.
  - Miscellaneous Compressor truck at Mantua, Mine at Ekalaka, Montana, Fred Churchill, G.L. Jepsen, 1957-1958; AR.1997.006; 484; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Misc. Med Rox, G.L. Jepsen, 1958; AR.1997.006; 481; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - MENAKER, G.L. Jepsen, 1959; AR.1997.006; 491; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Films of Field Trips -- 1960 Golden Valley, 1961 BH Basen Mesa, 638; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Films of Field Trips -- BH basin, S. Dakota, 1961; 640; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1962; AR.1997.006; 495; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1963; AR.1997.006; 475; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1963; AR.1997.006; 477; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
    includes Ed Lucilet talking. 16 mm.
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1963; AR.1997.006; 489; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1964; AR.1997.006; 485; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1964; AR.1997.006; 490; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1964; AR.1997.006; 496; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1965; AR.1997.006; 476; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Group at Notoungulata, Montana, G.L. Jepsen, 1965-1966; AR.1997.006; 482; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - 1968 Pan of Absaroka-Beartooth Mt.Front, clouds, crossing ditch on ladder, G.L. Jepsen, AR.1997.006; 478; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Cedar Pt., Red Lodge group at Rock Blvd., Avocet (bird) at dam in Sand Coulee, Montana, Pan of Mt. Front, G.L. Jepsen, 1968; AR.1997.006; 488; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Intro to WWS Project 1967-1968, 506; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 220)
    1 inch videotape.
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1970-1971; AR.1997.006; 487; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Undentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, 1971; AR.1997.006; 474; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Class Lectures: Philosophy 200 (Philosophy and the Modern Mind) lecture entitled "Theory and the Justification of Practice" and History 368 (The First Road to Modernization: England 1470-1690), portion of one lecture; and other miscellaneous recordings, 1974; AR.2013.027; 2369; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 233)
    Philosophy professor is James Smith; History professor is Lawrence Stone. Side A is Philosophy; Side B is History. Created by James L. Marketos '76. Compact cassette.
  - Class Lectures: Philosophy 200 (Philosophy and the Modern Mind) lecture entitled "Theory and the Justification of Practice" and History 368 (The First Road to Modernization: England 1470-1690), portion of one lecture; and other miscellaneous recordings, 1974; 2369; 1 Disc(s) (Box 233)
    Philosophy professor is James Smith; History professor is Lawrence Stone. Created by Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Compact disc.
  - Class Lecture: "The Significance of English Common Law," Joseph R. Strayer, 1974 April 11; AR.2013.027; 2366; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 233)
    Discussion of Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr.'s andThe Common Lawand. Created by James L. Marketos '76. Compact cassette.
  - Class Lecture: "The Significance of English Common Law," Joseph R. Strayer, 1974 April 11; 2366; 1 Disc(s) (Box 233)
    Discussion of Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr.'s andThe Common Lawand. Created by Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Compact disc.
  - Class Lecture: "The Significance of English Common Law," Joseph R. Strayer, 1974 April 3; AR.2013.027; 2365; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 233)
    Also features presentation by Jonathan Bush '1975, andThe Crown in Medieval Englandand; the reading course was put together by Jonathan Bush '75, Michael Benoff '76, and James L. Marketos '76. Created by James L. Marketos. Compact cassette.
  - Class Lecture: "The Significance of English Common Law," Joseph R. Strayer, 1974 April 3; 2365; 1 Disc(s) (Box 233)
    Also features presentation by Jonathan Bush '1975, andThe Crown in Medieval Englandand; the reading course was put together by Jonathan Bush '75, Michael Benoff '76, and James L. Marketos '75. Created by Seeley G. Mudd Library. Compact disc.
  - Class Lecture, Greek 103, John Keaney, 1974 November 13; AR.2013.027; 2367; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 233)
    Also includes latter half of a performance of Mozart's Requiem by the Princeton University Glee Club and the Princeton University Orchestra, conducted by Walter Nollner, date unknown. Created by James L. Marketos '76. Compact cassette.
  - Class Lecture, Greek 103, John Keaney, 1974 November 13; 2367; 1 Disc(s) (Box 233)
    Also includes latter half of a performance of Mozart's Requiem by the Princeton University Glee Club and the Princeton University Orchestra, conducted by Walter Nollner, date unknown. Created by Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Compact disc.
  - Class Lecture, Philosophy 304, by Ronald Dworkin, 1974 November 14; AR.2013.027; 2368; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 233)
    Side B is blank. Created by James L. Marketos '76. Compact cassette.
  - Class Lecture, Philosophy 304, by Ronald Dworkin, 1974 November 14; 2368; 1 Disc(s) (Box 233)
    Created by Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Compact disc.
  - Class Lecture, "Dante's Divine Comedy," by Robert Hollander, 1975 September; AR.2013.027; 2364; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 233)
    European Literature 303; recorded September 24 and 29, 1975. Created by James L. Marketos '76. Compact cassette.
  - Class Lecture, "Dante's Divine Comedy," by Robert Hollander. Two disc set, 1975 September; 2364; 3 Disc(s) (Box 233)
    European Literature 303; recorded September 24 and 29, 1975. Created by Seeley G. Mudd Manuscript Library. Compact disc.
  - Politics 302, S. F. Cohen, 1983; 1750; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 108)
    Compact cassette.
  - Near Eastern Studies: From Ancient Antiquity to Early Islam, 1984; 1645; 7 Audiocassette(s) (Box 105)
    General Overview, Imperial and Local Administration, Ethnic and Religious, Art, Rhetoric and Exegesis, Law, Theology and Conclusion. Compact cassette.
  - Molecular Biology Promo, 1985; AR.2001.063; 1281; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 24)
    VHS; Duration: 3.5 min.
  - Molecular Biology - Lab Footage, Building Under Construction, Class, Building Interiors, Interviews, 1985; AR.2001.063; 1318; 4 Videocassette(s) (Box 21-22)
    U-matic.
  - American Studies: Core Course Conference Day 1, 1985; 1640; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 105)
  - American Studies: Core Course Conference Day 2, 1985; 1642; 3 Audiocassette(s) (Box 105)
  - Architecture: "The Villas of Pliny: From Palladio to Posterity," Pierre Duprey, 1986; 1673; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 106)
  - Architecture: "Nature in the Italian Renaissance Garden," Claudia Lazzaro, 1986; 1674; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 106)
  - Architecture: "From the Piano Nobile," William LaRiche, 1986; 1675; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 106)
  - Architecture: "Urban Villas and Garden Palaces," Judith Kinnard, 1986; 1676; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 106)
  - Architecture: "Purism and Craftsmanship: Rossi and Scarpa," Patrizia Lombardo, 1986; 1677; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 106)
  - Humanities 205, W. R. Connor, 1986; 1695; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 106-107)
  - Classics, J. P. Vernant, 1986; 1697; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Classics, Round Table, J. P. Vernant, 1986; 1698; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Romance Languages, (Spanish) Speaker on Latin America, Josefina Ludmer, 1986; 1702; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Eric Foner, 1986; 1709; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Sidney Mintz, 1986; 1710; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Knight, 1986; 1711; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Carlos Monsivais, 1986; 1713; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
    2 copies. Compact cassette.
  - Latin American Studies, Carlos Monsivais, 1986; 1714; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Carlos Monsivais and A. Quinones, 1986; 1715; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Josefina Ludmer, 1986; 1716; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Josefina Ludmer, 1986; 1717; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Josefina Ludmer, 1986; 1719; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Josefina Ludmer, 1986; 1721; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Antonio Cornejo-Polar, 1986; 1723; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Jaime Concha, 1986; 1724; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Romance Languages, Ricardo Piglia, 1987; 1703; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Rebecca Scott, 1987; 1725; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Benitez-Rojo, 1987; 1727; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - American Studies, Kato Shuichi, 1987; 1922; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
  - American Studies, Kato Shuichi, 1987; 1923; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
  - American Studies, Kato Shuichi, 1987; 1924; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
  - Romance Languages, Robert Morrissey, and Closing Out Charlemagne: The Representation of History and the Discourse of National Origins in 19th Century Franceand, 1988; 1704; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Latin American Studies, Haiti Teach-In, 1988; 1728; 2 Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - Health Education, 1988; 1917; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 113)
  - Plasma Physics Lab and the Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor, 1989; AR.2001.067; 1491; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 38)
    Promotional video about the Plasma Physics Lab and the new Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor (TFTR), with footage of the interior, machines, and scientists at work. VHS; Duration: 9:18.
  - Plasma Physics Lab and the Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor, 1989; 1491; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 223)
    Promotional video about the Plasma Physics Lab and the new Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor (TFTR), with footage of the interior, machines, and scientists at work. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 9:18.
  - Plasma Physics Lab and the Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor, 1989; 1491; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 223)
    Promotional video about the Plasma Physics Lab and the new Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor (TFTR), with footage of the interior, machines, and scientists at work. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 9:18.
  - Plasma Physics Lab and the Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor, 1989; Digital Files: 1
    Item number: 1491. Promotional video about the Plasma Physics Lab and the new Tokamak Fusion Test Reactor (TFTR), with footage of the interior, machines, and scientists at work. Duration: 9:18.
    Mudd Manuscript Blog
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures, John T. Bonner, 1989 April 17-24; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
    Created by Joan S. Nielsen. Compact cassette.
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures by John T. Bonner, 1989 April 26-29; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures, John T. Bonner, 1989 April 3-5; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
    Recordings of Biology 204 lectures by John T. Bonner. Recordings were made by Joan S. Nielsen., who attended classes during her lunch hour. Created by Joan S. Nielsen. Compact cassette.
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures, John T. Bonner, 1989 February 10-13; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures, John T. Bonner, 1989 February 1-3; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures, John T. Bonner, 1989 February 6-8; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures, John T. Bonner, 1989 March 20-27; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
  - Recordings of Biology 204 lectures by John T. Bonner, 1989 March-April; AR.2012.117; 2402; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 237)
  - E. G. Conklin's speech, 1991; 9; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 47)
    Stenorette tape magazine; Duration: 45 min.
  - LGBA Pride Week Panel and "What is Lesbian and Gay Studies?, 1992; 582; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 44)
    VHS.
  - Math Chat, Frank Morgan/Derek Smith, 1997; 568; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 43)
  - John Bonner Composite Videos, 1997; AR.2012.117; 2403; 1 Disc(s) (Box 237)
    Video footage of slime mold slugs. 2-D Composite. DVD.
  - John Bonner Composite Videos, 1997; AR.2012.117; 2403; 1 Disc(s) (Box 237)
    Video footage of slime mold slugs. Capillarx Retreat-96 GFP/#2. DVD.
  - John Bonner Composite Videos, 1997; AR.2012.117; 2403; 2Videocassette(s (Box 237)
    2D Slime Mold Slugs. Hi8 video cassette.
  - John Bonner Composite Videos, 1999; AR.2012.117; 2403; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 237)
    Video footage of slime mold slugs. Capillarx Retreat-96 GFP/#2. Hi8 video cassette.
  - John Bonner Composite Videos, 1999; AR.2012.117; 2403; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 237)
    Video footage of slime mold slugs. 2D Composite Video. Hi8 video cassette.
  - Humanities 332, undated; 1699; 2Audiocassette(s) (Box 107)
  - University of Arizona, Mirror Lab II, 3.5 meter mirror casting, undated; 1947; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, undated; 1952; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Lake Louise and Lake Agnes, Canada, G.L. Jepsen, undated; 1954; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Train - Honeymoon of the Sciences, G.L. Jepsen, undated; 1955; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
    1200 meters. 16 mm.
  - Reproduction Among Mammals, undated; 1956; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
    Created by Erpi Classroom Films Inc. 16 mm.
  - Olive Fells Ranch, etc., G.L. Jepsen, undated; 1957; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, undated; 1958; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Canadian Trip, Vancouver, G.L. Jepsen, undated; 1959; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 186)
  - Palmer Lab, undated; 68; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 134)
  - Science Class--Graduate School, undated; 126; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 154)
  - MENAKER, G.L. Jepsen, undated; AR.1997.006; 479; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 173)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, undated; AR.1997.006; 483; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Unidentified lecture, G.L. Jepsen, undated; AR.1997.006; 486; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Flowers, G.L. Jepsen, undated; AR.1997.006; 492; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 174)
  - Films of Field Trips, undated; 633; 3 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Films of Field Trips -- Golden Valley, undated; 635; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Films of Field Trips -- Haddenham, undated; 636; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Films of Field Trips -- Trumpeter Swans, Jeep, and Bone Hill Collecting, undated; 639; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Films of Field Trips -- Collecting and Mounting Mastodon, undated; 641; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 175)
  - Films of Field Trips -- Fossil Hunting in Wyoming, undated; 644; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 176)
    Created by G.L. Jepsen - Dept. of Geology. 16 mm.
  - Films of Field Trips -- Fossil Hunting in Montana and Wyoming #2, undated; 645; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 177)
  - Fran Weber '57 English 204, undated; 661; 1 Phonograph Record(s) (Box 60)
    33 1/3 rpm album.
- Series 2: Alumni, 1916-2010; 234 items
  The Alumni series contains materials related to classes, reunions, and general alumni activities such as class/alumni trips. The Alumni series is arranged into two subseries: General and Reunions.
  - General, 1926-2000; 44 items
    Subseries contains materials related to general alumni events and activities, including class trips.
    Subseries is described in chronological order, with undated materials at the end of the subseries.
    - US--Butte, Spokane, Seattle, 1926; AR.1997.006; 220; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 171)
    - US--Los Angeles, Grand Canyon, Painted Desert, 1926; AR.1997.006; 222; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 171)
    - US--Crater Lake, Yosemite, Yellowstone, 1926; AR.1997.006; 224; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - US--Bismark, Yellowstone, Bustea, 1926; AR.1997.006; 225; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - US--Niagara to Yellowstone, 1926; AR.1997.006; 228; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - US--Butte, 1926; AR.1997.006; 229; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - Canada--Train to Lake Superior (Kettle Rally), 1927; AR.1997.006; 226; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - Canada--Port Arthur to Jasper, 1927; AR.1997.006; 227; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - Canada--Niagara to Jasper, 1927; AR.1997.006; 230; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - Horner Site - 1950, AR.1997.006; 233; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 172)
    - Alumni Day Proceedings, 1957; 602; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 79)
      1/4 inch magnetic tape, 7-inch reel.
    - Princeton Association Graduate Alumni, 1974; 34; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 58)
    - Oliver Quayle Discussion with Dartmouth and Princeton Alumni - Breed, 1974; 2349; 1 Videotape Reel(s) (Box 223)
      Dub reel 1 of 2. Created by Dartmouth College Video Recording. 1/2 inch video tape.